Welcome to this exercise task about class diagrams
or the syntax of class diagrams. In this case,
we have been given seven class diagrams, which
are simplified. So, there are no attributes and
no methods. These class diagrams simply consist
of boxes and have relationships between
them. So, we do not have to look at attributes
and methods here. We can assume that these
classes are well-formed. For instance, this A
class here shall be treated as a valid class,
and we just have to look at the connections
here. So, we have to justify our decision
if these class diagrams are valid just by the
syntax. For the first one, we have a composition
between A and B. So, A consists of B's. And
we have an aggregation where B's consist of A.
But this is not problematic. If it were just
compositions, then we would have cycled between
A and B, which is not allowed. But having an
aggregation here is not a problem. So, this one
here is a valid class diagram. So, consider the
next one. Here we have a composition where A's
consist of C's. And C consists of B's. And this is
not problematic in the first case. But then there
is an inheritance where B inherits from A. That
means B's are also A's. And when this happens,
then this means that they also inherit the
composition where A's consists of C's. And
this would mean that B's consist of C's whereas
C's consist of B's. And this is a composition
cycle. And that is why the second-class diagram
here is invalid. Let's consider the next one.
This one consists of three classes again.
And class B are compositions where B shall
be part of A and C at the same time. Because of
this one here, it is required for B's to have
an A. And it is also required for B's to have a
connection to C. So, that means B shall be part
of A and of C at the same time. And this is
not allowed as the composition rules are that
one part can only be a part of one
whole. So, this does not make sense.
So, we could argue that the class diagram
is valid. But if we say it's valid,
then we also have to admit that there is no
valid instance. So, we can also say this class
diagram is invalid. But if you say it's valid,
then you have to argue that there is no such case
where it would make sense at all. And that
is why there would be no such B existing.
We have two classes only in D. These classes
are A and B. And A shall inherit from B. And B
shall inherit from A. This is an inheritance
cycle, and inheritance cycles are not allowed. So,
this class diagram is invalid because it
does not make sense at all that B is an A,
and A is a B, and so on. There is no clear parent
class in this case. So this is not allowed.
Now, we have E, which is an aggregation
where A's are aggregated by A's. So,
this A class here is simply a self-aggregation.
Indeed, this is no problem. So, it would be
problematic for compositions. Cycles are not
allowed for compositions. It would be problematic
for inheritances. But it's no problem for
aggregation. Thus, we can say this one is correct.
Then we have the F class diagram. F
consists of the three classes again,
A, B, and C. And C shall inherit
from A. And C shall inherit from B.
Indeed, this is generally no problem. So, a
class can inherit from multiple classes. And for
abstract classes, it happens quite often that the
class has two interfaces. And this would be the
case here. So, interface A and interface B and C
inherit from two classes. And that's totally fine.
So, this is okay. And then we have G. Where we
have a constellation that looks roughly similar
to C. But this time, the compositions are the
other way around. So, B shall consist of C and
of A's. So, both parts belong to B. And if there
is a C, it has to have a connection to B. And if
there is an A, then it is actually a part of
B. But there is no problem with this because
a class can consist of multiple parts using
the composition. So, the composition can
be for multiple different parts. And
this is no problem at all. As a last note
on E here, when we consider this case here, if we
consider our picture, for instance, which consists
of subpictures, this could be something like this,
what we want to try when we have an aggregation of
A's to A's. So, if this would be the Picture type
that we had in tasks before, then we could say
when we compose them using the ampersand operator,
which was given in a video before as an example,
this could represent this one as well.
That's it for this task. Thank you very much.